Basket will come out. He will come go
house. I come realize say anytime Basket
reach house, he will carry phone.
He will come call me. You know say we no
get wife again.
So he will carry phone go come call me.
A-Y.
I'm home now.
I say eh?
This thing want to look like
relationship.
>> MC EDO PIKIN DILUTED. STAR BOY AND THE
LEGEND.
>> WITH A SHOUTING OVATION, [screaming]
WITH A CLAPPING OVATION, PLEASE CAN YOU
ALL GIVE IT UP FOR COMEDIAN
A-Y MAKUN.
>> [screaming]
[music]
>> ABOUT TALK MY E.
Benin City [cheering] make some noise
for Edo Pikin.
Omo, see see levels.
All right. That song where you take
welcome person, na God song be that one
no?
The daddy way they pamper, this song
where all na heavenly day.
Wow. See, oh boy.
Benin people they come out like this.
This is lovely.
I be
Na to come to show you be that oh.
I love this business.
I beg I come?
Oh boy, see. Wow, crowd where they
pamper.
Nice one. Nice one. Nice one. But
please, show some love for Candy Black.
He killed it.
He killed [applause] it. Yeah, he killed
it.
The industry
we are blessed with different talented
human resources. Now waiting we tell the
show be this oh.
>> [music]
>> What I
I'm not talking to you on a Zuzu.
Oh, me.
You know? I'll go find another then.
Yeah, yeah. I went to
primary school.
SOMEBODY ANYBODY TALK THAT PERSON HOLD.
HUH? How old I be?
You won't guess?
You say?
I'm just 27.
I want.
Who be that?
Okay.
Now you.
Uh
You know who be that?
Huh?
Who be that?
Natasha.
NATASHA BE THAT.
HUH? I JUST SAY I DON'T KNOW.
YOU WON'T GO HELP ME.
>> I can't touch her because
Yeah.
I see say I no know.
He won't come help me.
Oh boy. Oh boy, talk me.
Now I see movement.
I see Natasha movement.
I got this. I got this.
I got this. Lagos will COME TO BENIN.
>> [laughter]
>> AH!
AH! I DON'T TELL YOU, EH? THIS SOCIAL
MEDIA, EH? Now now go kill us.
All of una wey dey wey dey comment on
social media, now now wicked pass.
I go tell una why una wicked.
UNA THAT TWO WICKED. THEY FIRST start
with me and Basketmouth that year.
We no know wetin cause quarrel. We just
SEE OURSELF DEY FIGHT.
WE JUST SEE OURSELF DEY FIGHT. I KNOW
UNA go just go dey comment.
AY is an idiot. The other ONE GO
BELIEVE.
I SEE THEY BELIEVE THEY DON'T CALL AM.
BASKET is mumu.
Na so una use our head. We no even Today
we no know WETIN CAUSE QUARREL.
WE JUST SAY WE DEY FIGHT.
The same thing now now they do Davido
and Wizkid now.
UNA DEY ALWAYS DO THIS THING. And it dey
make una happy. I no know why they make
una happy.
IT DEY MAKE UNA HAPPY. I NO KNOW WETIN
THEY MAKE UNA HAPPY. Why people I say
now we DEY GIVE UNA ENTERTAINMENT.
UNA NO GET ANY OTHER PROBLEM UNA WANT
SOLVE? NO be everybody or those people
wey dey comment on social media. I'll
tell una why they talk this. This year
I'm taking it personal. Me and
Basketmouth, we no know wetin cause
quarrel. BUT GOD COME talk I will go
settle.
As soon
as we settle,
NOT TOO LONG, SHA.
PEOPLE COME STILL GO COMMENT SECTION.
THEY COME DEY COMMENT. WHY THEY NO GO
SETTLE?
WHY THEY NO GO SETTLE? THIS ONE DON'T
know say wife don't run. THIS ONE WIFE
DON'T RUN.
NOW NOW THEY WANT DO MEN SUPPORTING MEN.
I SAY WAIT.
WHAT UNA WETIN WE DO NOW?
FOR INSIDE THE SAME SETTLEMENT, OH. THEY
SAY SO, WHEN ME AND BASKET COME SETTLE,
I CAN'T DECIDE TO DO SHOW. I can't tag
the show. I name the show the good
the bad
and the ugly.
So, meanwhile, I put Basket and I go die
inside the show. Now, I go tell two of
them say me I don't take good, oh.
Between the two of una,
more now I know who go take ugly.
I don't know. I mean I mean between I go
die and Basket, who suppose take ugly?
Who?
I go die?
I go tell una they say be me. You people
are not loyal.
You people you are wicked.
That's how they begin drag WHO GO TAKE.
AND WHEN ME AND BASKET MAN COME SETTLE,
WE FINALLY SETTLE. UNA KNOW THAT
SETTLEMENT WHEN MEN they do. You know
men are men. We go dey form like say
everything dey okay. But women,
forget women side. If they quarrel, they
don't quarrel. If it happen, it don't
happen. Me and Basket Basket go come my
house. We no dey know waiting to talk.
But you know the way boys go do. Half a
guy, half a
half a half a half a man.
Basket go come my house. He go come go
house. I come realize say anytime Basket
reach house, he go carry phone.
He go come call me. You know say we no
get wife again.
So, he go carry phone go come call me. A
Y,
I'm home now.
I say eh.
This thing want to look like
relationship, oh.
>> [cheering]
>> BASKET,
WHEN BASKET SAY HE DON'T REACH HOUSE, I
SAY
I COME REALIZE MY BIRTHDAY COME COME.
BASKET COME SEND ME MONEY.
I say hey, Basket dey send me money.
You know, when I see see no be say the
money too big, but it means something to
me say fellow man send me money. Now,
now I come understand how women they me
money. Now now I come understand how
women they catch feelings
when men send them money.
I don't know what they happen. When I
see the money where Basket send me,
I come they catch feelings FOR BASKET
MOUTH.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHAT THEY HAPPEN.
NOW, WHEN ME AND BASKET GO THEY TALK FOR
PHONE, reach 1:00 a.m., nobody they cut.
I go take phone. I say Basket, you cut
it.
He go say why? You cut it.
NO, YOU CUT IT.
THAT'S HOW WE THEY PHONE THEY PHONE.
NOW,
YAWA COME GAS.
Na 30k first cos quarrel.
Yawa come gas. BASKET USED TO CALL ME
EVERY DAY.
TWO DAYS DON'T GO, BASKET never call me.
I say what did they go on?
NOW CARRY MY PHONE, NOW I CALL BASKET
MOUTH. BASKET,
WHERE ARE YOU?
IT'S BEEN TWO DAYS NOW YOU HAVE NOT
CALLED ME.
WHAT IS GOING ON? WHERE ARE YOU?
PUT IT ON VIDEO CALL. Let me see where
you are. WHO ARE YOU WITH?
I SAY RELATIONSHIP DON'T START.
But come to really think of it,
if
God forbid, I can't do that kind thing.
Let's assume say
we come they do that kind rubbish.
We come do that kind rubbish as man to
man. Between me and Basket mouth, I beg,
who go be the man and who go be the
woman?
I beg, I like to know. Who go be the
man?
I go be the woman?
I cover my nyash with the blood of God.
You see that? BECAUSE I GET NYASH.
WHEN I SEE ME SEE WAHALA,
SO BASKET, ME WORRY BOY.
Worry boy, me I boss over all of them.
They will go come come with that thing.
Now me go be the woman.
Well, ME WE LEAVE WE LEAVE BASKET STORY.
BUT ALL THE SAME,
I did talk something before. Now now
they go
basket will come come out. Then the next
thing, nine news just come out.
Comedian A Y
relationship have scattered.
I come.
My younger was the one who said A Y not
the rich comment, oh.
If you read comment, you go die, OH. I
SAID, "NO, I NEED TO KNOW WHAT THESE
PEOPLE THINK ABOUT ME."
I NEED TO KNOW BECAUSE THEY THEY FOLLOW
ME STAY. I NEED TO KNOW WHAT THEY THINK
ABOUT ME.
NOW WE GET
OH, but when I start to read comment
Now they just know say people they
comment. Please, if you are one of those
people that comment here, I beg raise
your up your hand.
Make I know the thunder we go fire you
here today.
WICKED PEOPLE.
THEY TORMENT ME, TORMENT ME, TORMENT ME
SO THEY I NO EVEN KNOW WHAT TO DO AGAIN.
ANY SMALL THING THEY DON'T COST ME.
NO BE ME SAY ME WOMAN GO NOW.
Any small thing they don't cost me. AT
THE END OF THE DAY, WHAT YOU COME PAY ME
BACK? ONE DAY, I WAKE UP. I SAY, "I BE
WORRY boy or die." Now die.
Anytime I get fine house, I go go
rooftop. I GO TAKE PICTURE FROM TOP OF
MY ROOFTOP. POST LIKE THIS. POST FOR
INSTAGRAM, PUT COMMENT.
LIFE GOES ON.
AS I PUT COMMENT FINISH, PUT THAT
CAPTION FINISH, LIFE GOES ON.
ONE MAN GO SAY, "OKAY, OH YEAH, GO
comment session."
As I go comment session, the one one I
first see
I take the picture I take my you know,
top roof, take picture and all that. One
guy put one comment, "Lonely at the
top."
I say, "Who's guy will laugh me this?"
WHO'S GUY WICKED PEOPLE BE THIS?
WAITING I DO NOW?
NOW DO AGAIN, I TAKE ANOTHER PICTURE
AGAIN. LOOK GOOD, PUT MYSELF TOGETHER.
Look good. I still put COMMENT AGAIN,
PUT CAPTION.
NO MATTER WHAT, the show goes on.
I say okay, go comment section. For
comment section, now one person say yes,
no matter what, the show goes on. You
[\h__\h] I be you no [\h__\h]
I say who's guy while I be this?
I don't KNOW WHEN I GO START TO THE
PRAY. FATHER LORD,
CAN SOMEBODY else just trend?
A WHITE TREND YOU DON'T TOO MUCH. I CAN
WANT YOU MIGHT BE THERE DON'T THE TREND
trend trend trend. Almost two months
plus. I go the pray to God. I go the
pray to God. I don't know say I DON'T
KNOW SAY GOD PUT NATASHA SOMEWHERE TO
HELP ME.
I DON'T KNOW SAY GOD PUT NATASHA
SOMEWHERE TO HELP ME. AS I THE TREND
TREND TREND, NOW I JUST WAKE UP ONE MORE
DAY PA!
NOW I JUST SEE INTERNET. NOW THEY SAY
TWO BABA DON'T JOIN OUR WHATSAPP GROUP.
AS I SAY I SAY TWO BABA DON'T SHAKE. YOU
KNOW SAY ME AND TWO BABA NOT THE SAME
NOT THE same
estate we the stay. See two baba, see my
house. Now first we the jump go inside
ah! I SAY THEY GO PA PA PA NOW NOW MY
NUMBER EVERYBODY GO THEY CALL. PA PA PA
HEY WHY WHAT IS GOING ON? WHAT IS
HAPPENING WITH TWO BABA? WHAT IS GOING
ON? WHAT'S GOING ON? CAN YOU GO AND
CHECK ON HIM? NOW SO WE WERE THERE.
YOU THEY CRAZE? WHEN my own happen he go
check on me?
So now me want go check ON AM. ME WHERE
BE LIKE SAY NA MY PRAYER POINT SO NOW I
PRAY SAY MAKE GOD HELP ME. ME AND
ANOTHER PERSON TREND. TWO BABA DON'T
TREND. THEY SAY PLEASE GO AND CHECK ON
HIM. MEANWHILE THE TWO BABA WHERE THEY
SAY ME I GO CHECK ON. He they Benin
here.
NA BENIN HERE WHERE NATASHA?
NATASHA DON'T CARRY PA FOR BENIN HERE.
THEY SAY ME I GO CHECK ON two baba.
But all this were entertainment. So put
your hands together for Natasha and two
baba. They don't tell you now
make everybody step down cease fire.
Cease fire.
When you cease your fire, clock it.
It's none of your business.
I am coming to Benin
to look for my own omonomose.
I wow.
How are you?
I'm coming to Benin to look for my own
omonomose.
You go give me?
Now this is what go give person problem.
>> [laughter]
>> OH, MISS DJ, YOU GET ONE? SEE NOW
IT GETS WHEN WE THEY DO UH-HUH meanwhile
I notice say for Benin now
more than all join Lagos people do what
they do.
All those girls for Lagos, Benin people
be like say when I dey airport they come
today I notice say Benin people don't
they start to
join them
to buy nyash.
Please. Please. If Lagos people they buy
everything know, they they buy lips,
they buy ear, they they even they buy
throat, they they buy everything.
Please.
I no get problem with nyash where they
buy you, but please for Benin, let me
just advise.
If you want to buy nyash, please buy
responsibly.
Please, buy nyash where your leg fit
carry.
Now the problem because you see some
people they walk around like cat [\h__\h]
the nyash GO SPREAD LIKE GOSPEL.
PLEASE, I SEE ONE FOR AIRPORT TODAY. I
say so una go say maybe na just got
back, abi?
Not be Benin person.
I just got back.
Okay, good. And I don't even they tell
people I or you go dey
or you go dey Benin?
Now better you go.
I go see my female where.
This one be like Al Pacino.
O Yibo, how are you doing?
You all right?
Is that the lady that captured you?
Yeah. Now you carry am come here do.
Nah. Do you know 2 Baba?
You know 2 Baba? Yeah. You need to have
some meetings with him.
You said?
He said I
They met at your wedding.
2 Baba
meet for your wedding.
2 Baba meet Natasha for your wedding.
ARE YOU SO YOU ARE THE AUTHOR AND
FINISHER?
>> [screaming]
>> SO NOW YOU
UH I BEG GIVE ME HER NAME and number.
>> [laughter]
>> So they met AT YOUR WEDDING. THAT'S VERY
GOOD.
Oh you guys are married for how many
years now?
A year.
They you meet a year.
2 Baba meet Natasha for your wedding.
They tell you say na that wedding 2 Baba
meet her.
A year.
>> [laughter]
>> OKAY. YOU BE LIKE SAY
OKAY. YOU know say this this show before
before we do
before we do anything because one no 2
Baba na my guy. Some people go don
defeat. Why is it why talking like no,
this are jokes. I'm not Daddy Freeze.
>> [applause]
>> I'm a true friend.
There's a difference.
Yeah. So, ladies and gentlemen, this
show is a special show
and I want us to applaud
Adopekin for making this possible.
>> [applause]
>> This is indeed a different kind of
December. And as a matter of fact,
I will stop every other performers who
want to wear what don't line up. It's
time to do something special. Adopekin.
>> Yeah. Where were you?
>> Senior man.
>> Marijuana.
>> Follow.
>> Uh-huh.
>> What year now?
I just see my leader.
>> All right.
>> A lot of party
you put it for something.
Uh so, okay. Now fake believe by you be.
Me where you at?
Me scholar. This are no good sense.
YEAH.
>> OKAY.
>> [screaming]
>> NO, NO, NO, NO, NO. NO, NO.
>> I I I perform I perform for you for I
say
>> You go first go ask. You first go You
first go ask. Say, "Okay, why you spend
9 years for university?"
>> Oh, which year you there?
>> Now you there where you there.
>> Upper last school.
>> That was undiluted, by the way.
>> Yeah.
>> Now me want to go for trouble. You carry
me come beneath to save me up.
>> the way that me two face? So, that be
I'm say the wedding.
Now me I'm say wedding now.
>> Wedding where that for me two face.
>> When I meet that that that I say I'm
traveling. Man, you no travel again.
Huh? You are being now.
That That's the power in the wedding. I
clap for Wesley. That's the king of
boys.
>> He said that I see meat 1 year ago.
>> Yeah. I know now we we they bring
different people.
Bring two face. This one I no they sing
for yummy.
Now she bring this one for us.
>> Okay.
>> Now one of the worst life be that now.
An empty street. An empty street.
Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait. I want I
want find out something. Where the guy
with the multimedia?
Play the karaoke way they there. I want
find out something. We go do our Yoruba
karaoke.
Then we'll come to our own
Naija karaoke.
I don't say they look time. We get time.
Now 3 minutes.
NO. NO. WAIT. THE SONG WILL PLAY.
WHERE MULTIMEDIA?
OKAY. Now we want confirm.
Put just dim the light. Oh yeah, play.
Play.
Let's do this karaoke together. Oh you
both on. Then we'll come to Naija own
together.
Are you guys ready?
>> Yes.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Boss, boss, BOSS, BOSS.
BABY TO SABI THINGS.
NOW SOMEBODY COME REQUEST SONG.
Now the song
It's sweet.
Nigeria own together. Dim the lights.
Play the next one.
Are you ready?
Are you ready? Let's do it together.
On the dance floor. On my shower remix.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Seven seven times.
>> [music]
>> Are you singing it?
That's level.
Top baby.
>> [music]
>> I love you Jesus.
>> Hey, my lord.
Stop, stop, stop, stop.
THAT IS A TRUE ROOKIE.
I don't give A DAMN ABOUT MUSIC. SO,
WILL YOU GO AND PAY FOR THIS KIND OF
KARAOKE?
>> [cheering]
>> YES? THEN PUT your hands together for
Nigeria, ladies and gentlemen. MC Edo
Pikin undiluted. Star Boy AND THE
LEGEND.
USELESS TRADITION WHEN YOU BE LIKE SAY
AS I GET THAT SO YOU GO FOLLOW.
MY WIFE GO GO [\h__\h]
INSTEAD OF THE MAN WAY [\h__\h] MY WIFE TO
DIE. THE TRADITION SAY NA ME.
>> [applause]
>> IT'S Edo in a cup with MC Edo Pikin.
Ladies and gentlemen, are you ready to
receive the legend, international,
ever blazing, forever young, forever
funny, forever witty, forever hilarious,
a provocateur OF EXTRAVAGANT HUMOR.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, IF YOUR HANDS ARE
NOT TOO BUSY WITH A CLAPPING OVATION, I
SAID THE LEGEND, WITH A SHOUTING
OVATION. COMEDIANS THAT WANT TO MAKE IT
IN LIFE, RISE UP TO YOUR FEET. PUT YOUR
[screaming] HANDS TOGETHER FOR
BIGGEST,
>> [screaming]
>> BOSS
AND GOD.
MAKE SOME NOISE.
>> [music]
>> AMEN.
AREA!
NOW THIS SMART YOU KNOW.
I DOING UH
I doing a call. Please pray as you go
for my brother.
I do picking. Let me say I do picking. I
beg clap for him.
When I clap for him, when I clap for
him.
We have bros, Julos.
Because I hear say they hail
Julos Agu.
Bro, respect to you.
I remember like I know say may you
stand up.
You know say you na bros.
So, sit down.
You are a good man.
And because of your heart,
I believe say na make God
give you second chance.
>> [applause]
>> You see sometimes when you do some
certain things,
you no they know
where that thing they go.
On a good day,
I go talk
about you.
But for now, please let us celebrate
my friend, my brother,
JULOS AGU.
>> [applause]
>> AREA!
AREA!
THEY CALL ME JUST NOW.
MC I do picking call me just now say
the legend,
the funniest,
low level no take package.
You go know when promoter no want pay
you money.
When somebody don't hype you like this,
>> [laughter]
>> you no go able to pay me the person for
balance self.
If you go do event for pastor, HE GO
SAY, "AH, THIS THING WHAT YOU DO SO, GOD
GO BLESS YOU."
NO JUST EXPECT BALANCE.
>> [laughter]
>> You don't pay you be that. But I'm very
very happy
Say we they do a do in a core.
We carry the event from Benin
to Lagos, from Lagos to all over the
world.
But we must say this, I beg.
Make we try maintain peace
for our state.
The things where they happen now, I'm
not really happy about it.
As I they do this event for here now so
for Edo in a core,
I go there proud to see say
they they do
Lagos in Edo.
If they no make Lagos state they
peaceful, we no go come here come
celebrate.
>> [applause]
>> Edo now our place.
We must make am
they more beautiful
for ourself and even for visitors
when they come our place go invest.
Say like this Lagos now, Benin people
just GET THINGS FULL HERE.
RELAX, NOBODY THEY CHASE THEM. POLICE NO
THEY PURSUE THEM.
GO BENIN, EVERYWHERE NOW POLICE.
BECAUSE OF
POLICE FOR BENIN CITY, JEHOVAH WITNESS
NO THEY PREACH AGAIN.
POLICE NO THEY TAKE I SEE THAT BAG. THAT
BAG where they carry, THEY NO BELIEVE
SAY ANYBODY WHEN YOU HOLD AN ALARM COME
THEY INSIDE. AND ANYBODY WHEN YOU HOLD
AN ALARM COME NOW YAHOO BOY.
AS I STAND HERE SO, I NO THEY MC Edo
picking no get amount when you want pay
me. He get money but he will not pay me.
Now my colleague. I no they try to want
come talk at this time of my age. 31
YEARS
HOLDING A MICROPHONE CRACKING JOKE. 31
[\h__\h] GOOD
YEARS.
THAT IS THE SUPPORT AND THE LOVE
WHEN I GIVE ME. I KNOW THEY TRY TO
IMPRESS YOU.
So I won't try to be funny.
I go die still funny. He not funny
again. I am not proving any points.
If you want laugh, go to YouTube.
Many things food there will going TO
MAKE YOU LAUGH.
IF YOUTUBE NOT MAKE YOU LAUGH, WATCH
PORN.
>> [laughter]
>> Then you relax yourself.
AT THIS STAGE
I WANT LEAVE THIS THIS JOB. NO SENSE
WORK.
YOU TALK SOMETHING SERIOUS THEY SAY
DON'T MIND HIM. HE'S HE'S VERY FUNNY.
I see now they talk now they say you
know they say I'm a comedian. He funny.
I just joke.
You know that THIS WORK I PLAN TO DO
BEFORE?
MY FUTURE PLAN WAS TO BE A GREAT
ENGINEER.
THE COUNTRY I CHANGE MY DESTINY.
LOOK AT THE TIME I do do do do what I be
to do. I sit down here now.
People when get problem like me
now I want make laugh. Who going to come
make me laugh?
>> [laughter]
>> Which people I go ARREST FOR THIS
COUNTRY? PLEASE SIR. MADAM.
THE PEOPLE WHEN THEY GO ARREST FOR THIS
COUNTRY I JUST WANT TO SAY THIS THEN I
leave. I not try come here come come I
just say verse for for for for for the
country. VERSE FOR THE PRESIDENT. VERSE
FOR OUR TRADITIONAL RULER. VERSE FOR
EVERYBODY. COUNTRY IS FRUSTRATE.
FRUSTRATION I FEEL IN THIS COUNTRY.
OUR GHOST SELF NOW COME WICKED PASS. THE
GHOST WE HAVE IN THE RIVER.
The ghost ARE NOT EVEN HELPING HELPING
SITUATION.
I JUST WANT QUESTION. SO, ALL THESE
GHOSTS, ALL THESE DEMONS, ALL THESE
THEY CANNOT KILL ALL THESE PRESIDENT AND
GOVERNOR?
NOW, ONLY PEOPLE WHEN SHEEP, WOMEN WHEN
[\h__\h] NOW GHOST THEY KILL.
WHAT KIND OF SOCIETY [\h__\h] AND GHOST?
>> [laughter]
>> USELESS USELESS TRADITION.
TRADITION THEY GET TO US THAT IS NOT
HELPING US.
AND THAT TRADITION IS WHAT IS AFFECTING
US TODAY. PEOPLE WHEN THEY COMPLAIN,
CELEBRITY MARRIAGE THEY CRASH. YES.
IT GO CRASH.
BECAUSE MOST OF US WE ARE SUFFERING FROM
THE PUNISHMENT OF OUR GREAT-GRANDFATHER,
OUR FATHER.
YEYE TRADITION.
YOU SAY THEY NO GO FEEL HUG WOMAN. ONCE
YOU HUG THAT WOMAN, YOU COMMITTED
UH
>> [laughter]
>> ADULTERY.
JUST HUG, OH. WHICH KIND DEMON BE THAT?
JUST HUG, OH. YOU SHAKE. THERE ARE SOME
TRADITION YOU DON'T EVEN SHAKE WOMAN. I
SAY, "NO." THEY USE THE TRADITION TO
ENSLAVE THE PEOPLE. MAKE WOMEN NOT TO BE
LIKE HUMAN BEING. I TELL THEM SAY, "IF
YOU LIKE THIS, I AM JUST PICKING THE
TRUTH TO FREE THE NEXT GENERATION."
>> [applause]
>> What is the beauty OF THE WOMAN GETTING
MARRIED TO A MAN? THEY USE THE TRADITION
TO PUNISH ALL THE WOMEN.
THE MAN GO DIE, THEY GO COME TELL THE
WOMAN MAKE THE WOMAN TAKE WATER, WASH
THE DEAD BODY, DRINK AM TO PROVE HER
INNOCENT. WHAT KIND OF BARBARIC
TRADITION IS THAT?
IF I SAY YOU WANT KILL YOUR HUSBAND, OH.
BECAUSE I DON'T KNOW WHY THIS THING JUST
MAKE YOU
>> THAT IS IT.
THE MAN DIED.
THE WOMAN DO NOT EVEN HAVE POWER TO
SHARE THE HUSBAND PROPERTY.
WHAT KIND OF TRADITION is that?
THE WOMAN DOES NOT HAVE POWER. THINK
ABOUT IT. IF YOU BE WOMAN, YOU MARRY THE
MAN, SPEND 70 60 YEARS WITH THE WOMAN.
SLOWLY FULLY WET SHE HAVE
THIS HAPPENED TO HER MOTHER.
WHEN THE FATHER DIED, THEY THROW HER OUT
OF THE HOUSE. SHE WAS A VERY YOUNG GIRL
GROWING. SHE SAW THESE THINGS WITH HER
EYES.
THEY ARE PREPARED to enter the world to
save for their FUTURE BECAUSE THEY KNOW
THAT THE TRADITION WILL NOT PROTECT
THEM.
LET THE UPPER OF BENIN
THE SULTAN OF SOKOTO
THE ONLY OFFICER
THEY SHOULD REVISIT THAT TRADITION.
They should revisit it.
>> [applause]
>> WOMEN CAN NEVER BE HAPPY. THEY STAY WITH
YOU FOR US AS HUSBAND AND WIFE. THEY ARE
SCARED OF THEIR TOMORROW. THEY DON'T
KNOW WHAT WILL happen to them.
Let it be equal.
>> [laughter]
>> NOW, THOSE PEOPLE THEY [laughter] SHOULD
JUST SUPPOSED TO KILL.
THOSE GYM INSTRUCTORS HERE OVER OVER
OVER OVER
COME.
THOSE THOSE GYM INSTRUCTORS
WHEN THEY DIRECT PEOPLE WHILE TRAINING
HER
If you think I am a liar, GUY, GO GYM
one day.
When you see waiting ALL THOSE GUYS
WHERE WE SAY if you see their chest
THE ONE WHERE THEY DRESSING LIKE THAT
SMALL WHETHER THAT boss has so in that
small What do they call that boss also?
I don't know what THEY CALL THAT
KNICKER. The thing will just tight the
waist, the the lap.
This is their rod.
Imagine this guy thin, oh.
You go hold this thing go just fast.
THAT THING THEY SHORT, OH.
YOU TAKE A FIRST person wife and the
gods they look there like that.
I GO THERE ASK MYSELF ONE QUESTION.
NO BE THIS tradition say if you work
person, THE PERSON GO DIE.
IT'S USELESS TRADITION IT BE LIKE SAY AS
I GET THAT SO YOU GO LOST AGAIN.
MY WIFE GO GO [\h__\h]
INSTEAD OF THE MAN WHERE [\h__\h] MY WIFE TO
DIE, THE TRADITION say na me.
Me where NO KNOW NOTHING.
ME WHERE NO KNOW NOTHING.
NA I GO COME DIE.
THIS IS VERY SERIOUS. THIS IS VERY
SERIOUS. NELSON MANDELA.
NELSON MANDELA, THE MOST LOVED MAN IN
AFRICA.
HE WAS IN PRISON FOR 27 years.
He not run for prison.
But he came out of prison.
But he not fit marry a wife back again
because of the fear of this tradition.
Believing that
if he wipe
Oh boy, NA YOU GO GO.
THE MAN THAT DESIGNED that tradition
they designed it for their selfish
interest. LET THEM REVISIT IT. NOTHING
CONCERN THE INNOCENT CHILDREN FOR THE
CRIME OF THE MOTHER. WE'RE GOING TO MAKE
BIKINI THEY SEEK.
IN FACT, THE MAN WHERE THEY GO MAKE THE
man go. [laughter]
Make them not touch my wife. Leave her.
YOU KNOW MAKE THEM NOT KILL MY WIFE.
WHETHER LEAVE MY WIFE. THAT MAN WHERE
THEY GO CLIMB. GO GYM.
TRADITION. ALL THE JUJU NO THEY SEE HER.
PERSON WIFE, OH. HEY J.
PERSON WIFE. GO GYM.
YOU GO JUST GO GYM YOU SEE HER.
UP.
WITH THAT YOUR YEAH YEAH.
BOSS HAS WHEN THEY HEAR YOU.
NO FORGET OH.
THIS.
TO DO PUT THERE YOUR OH.
>> [laughter]
>> THEY GO COME TO LIKE THIS.
DOWN.
AH.
YOU THEY SEE YOUR HAND OH.
PERSON WIFE, OH.
NOW YOU THEY DO. DOWN.
UP.
NOW, I NO KNOW THE KIND BLOOD.
WHERE THEY THOSE GYM [screaming]
INSTRUCTOR BODY.
BUT ME NO.
I AM SPEAKING FOR MYSELF.
MY OWN BLOOD.
And my own broccos.
I no know where from come.
If na me they do that down.
Down.
UP.
DOWN.
TODAY HEAR THEIR VOICE.
I SAY I GET THE GLASS I they wash. Me
just they WASH FOR THE
THAT GLASS. YOU KNOW SAY THEY GET GLASS
WHERE THEY THERE. THEY LIKE PERSON WIFE,
J. THEY LIKE PERSON WIFE. PERSON WIFE NA
THEY SLEEP FOR GROUND LIKE THIS OH. WITH
THE NAME OF OF EXERCISE.
PERSON WIFE, OH.
THAT WOMAN SO NO wear trouser.
Na that small
If you say THE PANTS
IT JUST SWELL UP SMALL.
THAT PLACE SO YOU BE like I will put
palm OIL FOR MY OWN.
MAN CRAZY CARRY PERSON WIFE LIKE THIS.
He go come they do leg like this.
THE WORST
ALL THIS ONE NO VEX ME.
YOU KNOW THE ONE WEY VEX ME? COME, TURN
LIKE THIS. YOU KNOW THE ONE WEY VEX ME
PASS? THE ONE WEY VEX ME PASS, I NEARLY
take I nearly go turn like this, just
turn. I nearly take wood, then knock the
guy. Now this one vex me pass.
Imagine now
short knicker
with that
denim
for here.
You come bend her like THIS FOR PERSON
FACE.
You know say if [laughter] you bend her
like this, the gap they show.
THE WOMAN I SAY THEY GO
THEY COME SAY THEY WANT THEY COME RAISE
THIS LEG LIKE THIS.
YOU SEE HERE SO?
IF THEY WANT do this exercise, they fit
spend 6 hours for here.
They come bend her like this.
Man wey devil they look, now my OWN ROD
THEY RAISE FOR FIRE.
Make I TELL THE ROD WETO I YELL AT HER
LIKE THEY WASH YOU.
THAT GUY STILL THEY WAKA TODAY. I yell
at her like I never do her anything.
LADIES [applause] AND GENTLEMEN,
THERE IS ONLY ONE POINT
I AM TRYING
UNDERSTAND THE FACT THAT
THE WAY
YOU'LL BE A MAN, THAT'S HOW WOMAN be
woman.
We must give them equal rights of
everything we share.
If we not MAKE THE WOMAN FEEL SECURE,
they will always look for protection,
something that they can save where they
go wrong go to protect their life.
YOU KNOW BE SAY THE CELEBRITY NOT GOOD.
NOT BE SAY WE NOT GOOD WHERE THEY LEAVE
US. BUT THEY KNOW THAT THEY'VE SEEN IT
THAT THEIR MOTHER CARE.
THEY SUFFERED THE MAMA. THE MOTHER DIED.
THEY THROW THE MOTHER LOAD ENTER
OUTSIDE.
And none of the children get anything
and the woman suffer. So from small some
of these girls already make up their
mind say, "I am going to secure my
future." And once they get what THEY
WANT, THEY TRAVEL TO a country where
they can have protection. That is why
most of them leave Nigeria, they travel
to America, they travel to United States
of America, they travel TO UK, THEY
TRAVEL TO A PLACE WHERE THEIR SECURITY
WILL BE PROTECTED.
I AM SPEAKING FOR MY NEXT GENERATION.
WE HAVE GONE THROUGH HELL, WE ARE THE
MEN.
I WANT TO SEE MY GREAT-GRANDCHILDREN. I
want TO SEE MY KIDS. I WANT to laugh
with them.
But they must REVISIT THE TRADITION.
YEAH, MAN.
WHEN THE MAN DIE, MAKE THE WOMAN GET THE
POWER to share the property. So that THE
WOMAN WILL FEEL BEING LOVED. IF WE NOT
DO AM, IT WILL STILL be the story of the
women, they came, they saw, they
suffered, and they died.
>> [applause]
>> Chase Edo in Edo with MC EDO PIKIN. BUT
AS YOU ARE [screaming] EDUCATED, YOU DEY
BUY GOLD GOLD
FOR TRAFFIC
32 KARAT
SIR, 32 KARAT
YOU KNOW WHAT HE SHOCK ME?
>> IT'S MC ADONKO KING ON DILUTE.
>> I REALLY LOVE YOU.
>> [cheering]
>> ALL RIGHT.
Let's start the show.
Wow.
All right.
I go perform for 5 minutes.
How many hours?
Let me get the show.
I do one hour, B.
Okay, just 20 minutes.
All right. Time to go. I wait.
DJ Alpha You do all right. This is a
good one. Let me clap for the DJ.
>> [applause]
>> I good. You good. You good. You good.
Ah.
You good.
My guy Alpha
How you doing?
I saw you last in London.
How are you doing?
Correct guy. That woman when you promise
for my show for Manchester
say you give her 2,000 pounds.
Huh.
The way the woman they call me be like
say na Benin the woman they stay.
How would a Nigerian promise person for
London? The person is called Kimi.
I beg I beg after the show.
Yeah, my integrity is at stake.
My full name
The comedy comedy catalyst just I want
to Nigeria
kingdom
By birth I be comedian and I funny.
Now we will start properly now. Which
table this seat?
Nice try.
Oh, now we have VIP seats.
VIP got the in front of table.
Table got the heavy
What God cannot do?
But different day different day.
Different day.
And I think I'm comfortable.
I know table.
Poor people can be happy with This
No deep play with the air the joke
before the table.
This life see how the way everybody they
happy. Life no pass like that. You did
Bible. Inside comedy enjoyment of life
eat, drink and be merry.
No be say you wicked. No be say you
wicked.
People they happy now. You they feel bad
say people they happy.
Yeah. Life no hard oh now you get
projector.
I don't be kidding. This one this place
is good down. I hear you buried the
thing.
You ask you never get money to
inconvenience us
I tell you what say actually not cause
now you want to hear people.
Okay, no no no say now where
every where they play they develop they
earn the cost.
My guy they stay four bedroom duplex.
Two swimming pool one for up.
One for down.
I have all these I I tell you
yearly payment.
He say 42 8.
I say for this island where we they stay
where the house they say not just far.
Say now stone throw from Chevron.
Stone throw.
I say I want to hear I say no you will
go from small.
I say I jump he say you will pass am.
I say where to not be you they go so he
say you just go from small.
I say you don't reach bell he say now
just small.
I say I'm from
now he say you just eat go from small.
I say but you say now stone throw he say
I depend on who tram.
So coming out talk about poor poverty
joke poverty joke poverty joke. You not
poor. Not to be poverty.
When you are poor you affect everything
about you.
Poor people don't get angry. It's part
of life.
Sometimes they will just provoke you
make am.
What is poverty? Your inability to
afford your needs.
Write am.
You know get sense again.
I tell am I they look me like say you
want to help me. Write it.
Poverty is your inability to afford your
name. Poverty is spelled v p
>> [laughter]
>> p
o
v
e
You need to type that. r o
t
y Say poverty.
>> Poverty
>> Correct guy.
See, when you are poor, you are fed
everything about you. Let me educate
you.
Do you know the poor have so many rules
and regulations?
The poor.
Now I make How you will go buy shoe? Who
sell am for you? You go tell them say go
so around.
Shoe Shoe pair of shoe.
You just SAY POOR POOR POOR TO GET TOO
MANY LAWS.
ALL THESE BECAUSE OF ALL THESE LAWS, YOU
GET MONEY?
YOU GET WHAT?
GO SO SHOE AROUND. THEY GO PUT
PROTECTOR.
YEAH, I don't they share your story.
If you get they tell his friend, who
tell about me?
THAT'S ONE THING ABOUT THE POOR. I KNOW.
I WAS THERE. I KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING.
NOT POOR.
EVERYTHING ABOUT POOR everything
everything You know ah
I THINK I BORN
I saw my PAPA BORN WITH 27 CHILDREN.
27 not sure ah
Now me they do well.
I say daddy, WHY YOU BORN US FOUR AS
LIKE THIS? HE SAY SO THAT I don't know I
don't know if he want that video
president will come from una.
And only poor man they WHAT? AND I I SEE
THAT ONE THAT CALL THE ANALYZER. WHY
POOR MAN THEY BORN MANY CHILDREN?
You know why? Because he that is down
fear no fall.
>> [music]
>> Anybody just CALL POOR MAN.
BECAUSE IF HE DIE, nothing they go fight
for.
That is why rich people
they live very careful. Are they like
chairman?
They don't call for any babe. Rich man
get your wife say
I get belly for you. First of all, you
no go talk to the girl for like one
week.
They think.
Which they hear one day tell me say my
daughter is 9 years. Eh?
9 years ago I they stay with who they
stay with person.
So, I will tell get the sexual
intercourse.
9 years?
HOW COME YOU NO TELL ME NOW? HE SAY THEY
WAIT FOR THE RIGHT TIME.
So my sister say why I never even really
define.
I say okay.
Make we go do DNA. I don't know say DNA
na for rich people.
It cost too.
It cost dollar bill.
As I reach the hospital
I just see one with four children. THE
MAN THEY SHOUT, "FOR WHAT?
AM I SELLING THEM?"
I DON'T KNOW WHY THE MAN THEY SHOUT.
NOW your car you take and come out. Then
they say, "You, I will carry you there."
They say, "Which time you want to do?" I
say,
"DNA." They say, "Which type?"
I don't know say DNA will get type or
what.
>> [laughter]
>> You know SAY NOW THEY GET POLICE CASE,
THEY KNOW WHEN THEY renovate police
station.
Now I say, "Hey, I want the I say,
'Which type they they say they get
paternity?'"
Not be war. I don't be the one who put
you for front, so you know why I put you
here.
They say, "Paternity and legal." I say,
"We make the difference." They say,
"Paternity na to know who born am, while
legal in case you want to use the
picking travel."
All right?
Now it's okay, paternity. I go to say go
ship.
And the girl take laptop, pa pa pa. Now
I say, "750."
"750?"
"Paternity."
Now I look the girl.
Me and my daughter, we resemble.
I say, "Lulu."
She say, "Daddy." I say, "Let's go."
Now I do the jogging. I say, "Sir, you
not doing it again." I say, "No they see
our eye."
>> Daddy, where the papa? [singing]
>> Do you know the way? The girl we read
from front line, my picking say,
"Daddy." I say, "Uh, you funny die." I
say, "Come out."
>> [music and singing]
>> I GO UP. DO YOU KNOW THE WAY? POVERTY
ALL GOOD, OH JESUS.
POVERTY.
Do you know even rich men? Sometimes
rich men will just carry girl. Rich men
know no worry, if you do what you do.
Rich man.
>> RICH MAN.
NO, NO, NO.
NO, NO.
You don't fly before or come back on
witchcraft. You don't fly.
Now one person.
THEY HEAR NOW. RICH MAN.
THE NEXT MORNING
I WANT TO GO.
OH GOD.
BECAUSE
hotel ready.
Now you know say when girl wake up
Please, let's celebrate [clears throat]
our shower.
>> [music]
[singing]
>> You know say
You carry girl around four.
5:30 she don't wake up.
Now they they call them runs girl. They
always running.
You there with your wife now they laugh
like that. You go explain this joke
later.
You know say they GO WAKE UP. AS THEY
WAKE UP TO IF YOU BE RICH MAN OH TO TALK
TO THEY HAVE THEM.
THEY THEY LOOK like they don't like it.
Good eating. Ah, me no vex oh.
You see they no they want me rich man
vex.
You see you see am.
She say poor create rules for the rich.
Now make when RICH MAN
CALL WHEN YOU CALL NOW ALL THE POOR MAN
HERE. WHEN YOU CALL RICH MAN
AS YOU CALL AM YOU NO PICK YOU NEED
CREATE POSITIVE reason for am.
You be like say they meeting.
>> [music and singing]
>> Like two weeks.
JESUS! POOR PEOPLE
Say ah, you be like say it meet you.
Man give am two hours.
But me you call a fellow friend.
As maybe you go dey [\h__\h] now.
EVERYTHING GET RULES.
POOR MAN NO DEY DO QUICKIE. Quickie is
for rich men.
Where poor man dey rush go?
IN THE MORNING THE GIRL GO SAY, "SEE, I
WANT TO GO. YOU SEE OH." YOU NO TOUCH
THE GIRL. SAY, "OPEN THAT DRAWER." THE
GIRL GO OPEN AM. "TAKE 500 dollar there.
DO YOU HAVE NAIRA?" HE SAY, "NO." "OPEN
THE OTHER DRAWER. TAKE 20,000 there for
your cab." THE GIRL NO GO.
NOW THE GIRL GO DEY SAY, "IF YOU DEY
WITH ME HERE, eh sir sir, can I have
your
Can I have your number?" The guy say,
"No no no no worry. No worry. It's fine.
It's fine. Ah, God. I go reach you."
Imagination won't kill me.
TEST ME. FOR MY RICH MAN. HELLO.
POOR MAN.
POOR MAN. EARLY [clears throat] MORNING.
EARLY OH, MONDAY MORNING. OH, MONDAY
MORNING.
How you go carry out your shower on
Sunday?
On Monday when people dey take life
serious.
You Now Now the annoyance dey wake
neighbor.
As soon as I come out of the shower dey
hold him trouser.
He dey drag am. You dey hear the guy dey
shout.
They drag out you to hear the guy they
I no go pay. I NO COME.
I NO COME.
THE GUY WILL GO SAY, "NA MY FAULT SAY
YOU NO COME? NA MY FAULT NO SAY I NO DO?
NO SAY I NO DO? EVEN HERE I LICK, YOU
COME?"
NA ARGUMENT OH.
I know say poverty be like WhatsApp
group.
EVERYBODY AROUND THE POOL.
AS THEY ARGUE, YOU SAY NO NO BE FREE
WHEN THEY WORK OUT THE COLOR. NA HIM
THEY CALL THEM OH. FRIDAY, COME.
How many times be day break? How many
times? How many times they day [\h__\h] day
break? How many times? That guy will go
say, "If you no day good mood, four
times."
>> [music]
>> Let me speak of poverty, Holy Ghost.
Jesus.
Life too sweet. DJ, DJ, you day try oh.
I hope say they pay you well oh.
Because you day Which one be sure sure?
No be you can say no say na 80K. Okay.
You know say na no get money they sit
down near speaker.
When we tell say what do you care for?
But no, LET'S THINK ABOUT IT.
NOW, THE BEAUTY OF SEX IS ON RELEASE.
Am I right? No they say, "Ah, you no see
wet time day?"
Okay, now this guy turn out with the
turn out about coming of Jesus.
Okay, you day feel me abi?
How person will they take tramadol to
masturbate? Tramadol.
You want to see last.
>> So I know the one when they repay me.
I bet say go dey masturbate the same
style.
Ah, poor people dey suffer, oh.
Now, LISTEN TO ME. YOU CANNOT BE
LEARNED.
NO, OKAY. LET ME PUT LET ME PUT IT THIS
WAY. NO MATTER HOW LEARNED YOU ARE,
if you meet illiterate, you need to
condescend to become illiterate to have
a discussion. Am I communicating?
BECAUSE THE ILLITERATE NO FIT ACT AS
LEARNED.
OH, GOD. I hope I'm not too intelligent
for you guys.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. People no good cuz you
see there I dey get
That SORT OF EDUCATION BE THE ONE WHO NO
GO DEY FEEL BAD, OH.
SIT DOWN DEY SHOUT WORD, WORD. You no
hear, oh?
No be for Abuja I land. Now I want get
One girl say be 21 years. Girl talk to
me. Wow, my daddy introduce me to your
page on YouTube. Your jokes are
intelligent. I love your jokes. This,
this, this. I call the phone star. Now
the girl speak one English. You must be
sapiosexual.
I never hear that before, oh.
Mumu me, I go dey say yes, oh. I'm
sapio.
He say na sapio. He say na English, oh.
You no get sense again? English, oh.
Best way to make connection.
WHAT?
AH, YOU GO GO BUY [screaming] AS YOU ARE
EDUCATED. YOU DEY BUY GOLD GOLD CHAIN
FOR TRAFFIC, GOLD.
FOR TRAFFIC.
>> 32 KARAT
32 KARAT
YOU KNOW WHAT HE SHOCKED ME? AS HE GOT
BABY FINISHED NOW, HE WENT AND GOT
GLASSES. Oh God, I like you. Where are
you from? I'm not wearing them.
>> [music]
>> The one where he shocked me, how you buy
dog for traffic. Dog go
when you don't know his history.
My friend buy dog for traffic. You know
say 2 years now, he never back.
We carry am go vet. They tell us say the
dog na deaf and
All right.
I don't begin about
They don't come.
You know say they They don't come since
Oh, they come before I come.
>> [music]
>> All right.
All right. Are you guys having fun,
right? It's been a beautiful morning,
right?
Feel very free. Life no really Eh,
if your neighbor they fry stew this
Christmas, no worry. Just buy onions.
I did they do this share. Bye-bye. If
you fry 3,000 na onions
>> It's MZ and Dorobucci on Dial Tune.